<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working papers | Juergen AMANN</title>
    <link>https://amannj.github.io/tag/working-papers/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amannj.github.io/tag/working-papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Working papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amannj.github.io/media/icon_huba55e4d0e29128b607415a99236d03d8_2095_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Working papers</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/tag/working-papers/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price Adjustment in the Euro Area in the Low-Inflation Period: Evidence from Consumer and Producer Micro Price Data</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/price-adjustment-euro-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/price-adjustment-euro-area/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper documents five stylised facts relating to price adjustment in the euro area, using various micro price datasets collected in a period with relatively low and stable inflation. First, price changes are infrequent in the core sectors. On average, 12% of consumer prices change each month, falling to 8.5% when sales prices are excluded. The frequency of producer price adjustment is greater (25%), reflecting that the prices of intermediate goods and energy are more flexible. For both consumer and producer prices, cross-sectoral heterogeneity is more pronounced than cross-country heterogeneity. Second, price changes tend to be large and heterogeneous. For consumer prices, the typical absolute price change is about 10%, and the distribution of price changes shows a broad dispersion. For producer prices, the typical absolute price change is smaller, but nevertheless larger than inflation. Third, price setting is mildly state-dependent: the probability of price adjustment rises with the size of price misalignment, mainly reflecting idiosyncratic shocks, but it does not increase very sharply. Fourth, for both consumer and producer prices, the repricing rate showed no trend in the period 2005-19 but was more volatile in the short run. Fifth, small cyclical variations in frequency did not contribute much to fluctuations in aggregate inflation, which instead mainly reflected shifts in the average size of price changes. Consistent with idiosyncratic shocks as the main driver of price changes, aggregate disturbances affected inflation by shifting the relative number of firms increasing or decreasing their prices, rather than the size of price increases and decreases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Energy Prices on Firm Competitiveness: Evidence from Chile </title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper analyzes the impact of changes in energy prices on the competitiveness of manufacturing firms in Chile. Using the Chilean Annual National Industrial Survey data, the paper illustrates that, first, increases in energy prices generally do not hurt firm competitiveness. Second, the impact of energy prices depends on the fuel type—while electricity price increases are negatively correlated with firm outcomes, fossil fuel price increases have a positive association with investment and firm productivity, a result that is consistent with the strong version of the Porter hypothesis. Third, these effects are heterogeneous and vary by firm attributes such as size, ownership and location. Fourth, investigating non-linear patterns in firm outcomes based on the level of energy prices, the findings show that the positive correlation between fossil fuel price increases and capital upgrading is particularly pronounced when energy prices are at relatively low levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the socio-economic impact of the circular economy through input-output modelling - Evidence from developing countries</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/nice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of circular economy is gaining growing importance in the policy debate as the need to focus the international effort to accomplish the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 12, “Responsible production and consumption”, has become increasingly paramount. Many international organisations are now fully involved in implementing technical cooperation projects to reduce the use of materials for industrial output. However, while there is a wide consensus that the prevailing production paradigm cannot sustain the current industrial practices indefinitely, the policy space for the promotion of the Circular Economy is hampered by the lack of a complete understanding of winners and losers in international or  omestic value chains and the overall net benefits of the undertaken measures. This paper develops the NICE (National Impacts of Circular Economy) tool, which is based on the Eora input-output data to analyse how technical cooperation projects, which are aimed at more sustainable use of materials, affect economic and social indicators. Whereas the long-term transition towards a circular economy and a more efficient economic system is less controversial, the results of this study help deepen the understanding of the possible short-term impacts, especially for countries struggling to climb the ladder of development. Strategic implications for a reconciliation of economic, social and environmental targets for inclusive and sustainable industrial development and a full accomplishment of the SDG 9 are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanded Real Value-added Data for Manufacturing: A New Approach to Measuring Sub-Sectoral Manufacturing Development</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/real-value-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/real-value-added/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a new single deflation method to expand the availability of subsectoral real value-added data using UNIDO’s Industrial Statistics Database INDSTAT (2021). We derive a single deflator consistent with current national accounting practices and is self-contained, i.e., only requires data available via INDSTAT. We also discuss various extensions to further improve data coverage. Our approach enables us to derive an extensive data set with notably higher data coverage vis-a-vis other large cross-country data sets, particularly for low(er) income economies. This allows us to measure the performance of the manufacturing sector in unprecedented detail and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firm-level Effects of Energy Price Increases: a Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/firm-level-energy-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/firm-level-energy-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy subsidy reforms can raise important challenges for firms. A large academic literature has evolved to study these effects. This paper provides a summary of that literature and recommendations for future evaluations of policy impacts&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth and Volatility; Why Duration Matters for Long Run Macroeconomic Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/growth-volatility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/growth-volatility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper we revisit the busy debate over the relationship between volatility and growth, to separate out the effects on growth that come from short run and long run episodes of uncertainty. Employing this time series perspective, we reconcile the theoretical ambiguities and explain the conflicting differences in empirical studies of this important linkage. We suggest that the relationship depends on the type of volatility responsible for driving economic fluctuations; volatility that reflects longer run positive characteristics is positively associated with economic growth, with shorter spells of uncertainty associated with poorer macroeconomic outcomes. Stabilisation policy needs to discriminate between good volatility and bad volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetary Policy and Green Investment Impacts: Evidence from Exchange-Traded Funds</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/green-etfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/green-etfs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper we revisit the busy debate over the relationship between volatility and growth, to separate out the effects on growth that come from short run and long run episodes of uncertainty. Employing this time series perspective, we reconcile the theoretical ambiguities and explain the conflicting differences in empirical studies of this important linkage. We suggest that the relationship depends on the type of volatility responsible for driving economic fluctuations; volatility that reflects longer run positive characteristics is positively associated with economic growth, with shorter spells of uncertainty associated with poorer macroeconomic outcomes. Stabilisation policy needs to discriminate between good volatility and bad volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing the debt threshold hypothesis: A structural break threshold Granger causality test under cross-sectional dependence</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/granger-causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/granger-causality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper we revisit the busy debate over the relationship between volatility and growth, to separate out the effects on growth that come from short run and long run episodes of uncertainty. Employing this time series perspective, we reconcile the theoretical ambiguities and explain the conflicting differences in empirical studies of this important linkage. We suggest that the relationship depends on the type of volatility responsible for driving economic fluctuations; volatility that reflects longer run positive characteristics is positively associated with economic growth, with shorter spells of uncertainty associated with poorer macroeconomic outcomes. Stabilisation policy needs to discriminate between good volatility and bad volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
