<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research | Juergen AMANN</title>
    <link>https://amannj.github.io/category/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amannj.github.io/category/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amannj.github.io/media/icon_huba55e4d0e29128b607415a99236d03d8_2095_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/category/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price selection on the two sides of the Atlantic</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/price-setting-atlantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/price-setting-atlantic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of monetary policy depends crucially on the degree of price flexibility. This flexibility depends on the frequency of price adjustments, as well as the adjustment magnitude of the prices which do change (known as price selection). This column uses granular data from the euro area and the US to quantify the degree of price selection. Accounting for price selection increases price flexibility estimates by around one-third in both regions, with a higher flexibility in the US. The findings are consistent with the differences in food inflation during the Covid-pandemic across the US and euro area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://cepr.org/voxeu/columns/price-selection-two-sides-atlantic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding publication &lt;em&gt;Price setting on the two sides of the Atlantic - Evidence from supermarket scanner data&lt;/em&gt; (Journal of Monetary Economics, 140) is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/publication/price-setting-atlantic&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The socioeconomic impact of circularity in developing countries</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/impact-circularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/impact-circularity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://iap.unido.org/articles/socioeconomic-impact-circularity-developing-countries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The socioeconomic impact of circularity in developing countries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we introduce a novel tool, built on granular firm-level data and Input-Output modelling, to assess the economic, social and environmental impact of Circular Economy (CE):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The circular economy is critical to ensuring green and just socioeconomic outcomes through decoupling economic growth from increased resource use. In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eea.europa.eu/publications/sustainability-transition-in-europe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recent report&lt;/a&gt;, the European Environmental Agency discusses that the transition to the green and circular economy (CE) is driven by multiple environmental, demographic, technological, fiscal and financial transitions occurring in different sectors and geographies. CE may play a pivotal role in this transition because of its potential “triple positive impact” on economic growth as well as environmental and societal outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://iap.unido.org/articles/socioeconomic-impact-circularity-developing-countries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding working paper &lt;em&gt;Assessing the socio-economic impact of the circular economy through input-output modelling - Evidence from developing countries&lt;/em&gt; is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/nice&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A firm-level perspective on industrial resilience in a crisis</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/industrial-resiliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/industrial-resiliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://iap.unido.org/articles/firm-level-perspective-industrial-resilience-crisis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A firm-level perspective on industrial resilience in a crisis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, investigate the significance of industrial capabilities for robust growth during Covid-19:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History has shown that health and economic shocks are recurrent events; robustness to one such shock must be followed by preparedness for the next one. Accordingly, “the new normal” is a phrase that has been used throughout the COVID-19 pandemic to signal the need for fundamental change to follow the crisis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iap.unido.org/articles/building-socio-economic-resilience-through-industrial-capabilities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Resilience at both the government and sector levels&lt;/a&gt; can create conditions for countries to better withstand and recover from shocks. Our research based on World Bank data shows that manufacturing firms in countries with stronger industrial capabilities—proxied by higher Competitive Industrial Performance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.unido.org/cip/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CIP&lt;/a&gt;) scores—were more likely to remain in operation and experienced higher growth rates (or lower losses) in employment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://iap.unido.org/articles/firm-level-perspective-industrial-resilience-crisis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This piece is part of the IAP IDR2022 series, based on UNIDO&amp;rsquo;s flagship &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unido.org/idr2022&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Industrial Development Report (IDR) 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing firms shouldn’t fear the true cost of fuel – here’s why</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/true-cost-fuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/true-cost-fuel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unido.org/stories/manufacturing-firms-shouldnt-fear-true-cost-fuel-heres-why&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manufacturing firms shouldn’t fear the true cost of fuel – here’s why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we analyse the effect of energy price increases on firm-level productivity in Oman:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIDO-led research in collaboration with the World Bank provides concrete evidence that removing fossil fuel subsidies would not only make environmental sense but would also improve firms’ economic performance. New firm-level data from Oman show that higher fuel prices are not a drag on competitiveness. In fact, reducing subsidies and allowing fuel prices to rise could ultimately aid the post-COVID-19 recovery. This is because, according to the data studied, higher fuel prices drive business upgrading, leading to a boost in productivity. They could also encourage manufacturing companies to switch to the kind of long-term sustainable efficiency practices needed to stop climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unido.org/stories/manufacturing-firms-shouldnt-fear-true-cost-fuel-heres-why&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding publication &lt;em&gt;Switching it up: The effect of energy price reforms in Oman&lt;/em&gt; (World Development, 142) is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/publication/switching-it-up&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effects of energy prices on firm competitiveness in Chile</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/energy-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/energy-chile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/developmenttalk/effects-energy-prices-firm-competitiveness-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The effects of energy prices on firm competitiveness in Chile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we analyse the effect of energy price increases on firm-level productivity in Chile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firms are key to addressing Chile’s sustainability challenges and realizing its ambition of carbon neutrality by 2050. Switching to more sustainable production is essential to reducing vulnerability to environmental shocks and developing new areas of comparative advantage. In a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10986/39808&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recent working paper&lt;/a&gt;, we illustrate minimal trade-offs between productivity and energy prices, and a positive relationship between productivity and investments with fossil fuel prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/developmenttalk/effects-energy-prices-firm-competitiveness-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La versión en español está disponible &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/es/latinamerica/efectos-del-precio-de-la-energia-en-la-competitividad-empresarial-en-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;aquí&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding working paper &lt;em&gt;The Effects of Energy Prices on Firm Competitiveness: Evidence from Chile&lt;/em&gt; is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10986/39808&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World Bank Policy Research Working Papers&lt;/a&gt; portal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
