<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy prices | Juergen AMANN</title>
    <link>https://amannj.github.io/tag/energy-prices/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://amannj.github.io/tag/energy-prices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Energy prices</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://amannj.github.io/media/icon_huba55e4d0e29128b607415a99236d03d8_2095_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Energy prices</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/tag/energy-prices/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Energy Prices on Firm Competitiveness: Evidence from Chile </title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper analyzes the impact of changes in energy prices on the competitiveness of manufacturing firms in Chile. Using the Chilean Annual National Industrial Survey data, the paper illustrates that, first, increases in energy prices generally do not hurt firm competitiveness. Second, the impact of energy prices depends on the fuel type—while electricity price increases are negatively correlated with firm outcomes, fossil fuel price increases have a positive association with investment and firm productivity, a result that is consistent with the strong version of the Porter hypothesis. Third, these effects are heterogeneous and vary by firm attributes such as size, ownership and location. Fourth, investigating non-linear patterns in firm outcomes based on the level of energy prices, the findings show that the positive correlation between fossil fuel price increases and capital upgrading is particularly pronounced when energy prices are at relatively low levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firm-level Effects of Energy Price Increases: a Literature Review</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/firm-level-energy-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/firm-level-energy-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy subsidy reforms can raise important challenges for firms. A large academic literature has evolved to study these effects. This paper provides a summary of that literature and recommendations for future evaluations of policy impacts&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching it up: The effect of energy price reforms in Oman</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/publication/switching-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/publication/switching-it-up/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufacturing firms shouldn’t fear the true cost of fuel – here’s why</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/true-cost-fuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/true-cost-fuel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unido.org/stories/manufacturing-firms-shouldnt-fear-true-cost-fuel-heres-why&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manufacturing firms shouldn’t fear the true cost of fuel – here’s why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we analyse the effect of energy price increases on firm-level productivity in Oman:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIDO-led research in collaboration with the World Bank provides concrete evidence that removing fossil fuel subsidies would not only make environmental sense but would also improve firms’ economic performance. New firm-level data from Oman show that higher fuel prices are not a drag on competitiveness. In fact, reducing subsidies and allowing fuel prices to rise could ultimately aid the post-COVID-19 recovery. This is because, according to the data studied, higher fuel prices drive business upgrading, leading to a boost in productivity. They could also encourage manufacturing companies to switch to the kind of long-term sustainable efficiency practices needed to stop climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unido.org/stories/manufacturing-firms-shouldnt-fear-true-cost-fuel-heres-why&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding publication &lt;em&gt;Switching it up: The effect of energy price reforms in Oman&lt;/em&gt; (World Development, 142) is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/publication/switching-it-up&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effects of energy prices on firm competitiveness in Chile</title>
      <link>https://amannj.github.io/post/energy-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://amannj.github.io/post/energy-chile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/developmenttalk/effects-energy-prices-firm-competitiveness-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The effects of energy prices on firm competitiveness in Chile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we analyse the effect of energy price increases on firm-level productivity in Chile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firms are key to addressing Chile’s sustainability challenges and realizing its ambition of carbon neutrality by 2050. Switching to more sustainable production is essential to reducing vulnerability to environmental shocks and developing new areas of comparative advantage. In a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10986/39808&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recent working paper&lt;/a&gt;, we illustrate minimal trade-offs between productivity and energy prices, and a positive relationship between productivity and investments with fossil fuel prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/developmenttalk/effects-energy-prices-firm-competitiveness-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the complete article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La versión en español está disponible &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/es/latinamerica/efectos-del-precio-de-la-energia-en-la-competitividad-empresarial-en-chile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;aquí&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the corresponding working paper &lt;em&gt;The Effects of Energy Prices on Firm Competitiveness: Evidence from Chile&lt;/em&gt; is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://amannj.github.io/working-papers/energy-chile&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hdl.handle.net/10986/39808&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World Bank Policy Research Working Papers&lt;/a&gt; portal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
